Dennis A. Smallwood

Phone: 801-717-5808

Email: <u>dsmallz9698@gmail.com</u>

Objective

Highly self-motivated and goal-oriented professional seeking a long-term career in software engineering building IT enterprise products for an exciting growth company.

Summary

A results-driven, customer-focused, and loyal employee with a track record that demonstrates strong analytical and interpersonal skills. Excellent problem-solver with the ability to quickly grasp complex systems and resolve critical issues. Considerable experience in customer relations management involving large corporate and international clients.

Technical Summary

Skills

Java, Python, C#, J2EE, Hibernate, JSP, Servlets, SOA, SOAP, ReST, XML/XSL, JSON, Java Swing

Operation Systems

Windows and Linux cross-platform programming

Languages/Databases

Java, Python C#, .NET, C++, SQL, MySQL, MSSQL, Oracle, Sybase, GWT-EXT

Tools

Maven, SVN, Github, Ant, Agile programming, Eclipse, IntelliJ

Professional Experience

November 2013 – current Attachmate

Senior Software Engineer

- Integrated into third party virtual machine (VM) software such as Amazon EC2, XEN, Hyper-V 2012, AWS, VMware, and Citrix to manage VMs via our Cloud Management product called NCM.
- Bash scripting that manipulates virtual machines allowing full automation of VM operations such migrate, clone, network configuration, and adjusting VM settings such memory and storage.
- Python scripting that is responsible for the entire VM automation stack for our client/server model
- Provided product capabilities via web services and ReST interface
- Agile programming experience, specifically using SCRUM model

July 2005- 2013 Novell, Inc

Senior Software Engineer

- Lead programmer and team lead for several integration projects that completed on time and with quality
- Winner of Department Hackweek Projects in 2012 and 2013, which later were the foundation of marketable product features
- Developed plug-in adapters into third party systems such as AWS via SOAP, JNI, and REST interfaces
- Managed the ZENworks build system while reducing build downtime to avoid costly delays to entire product test team
- Reduced critical customer issues from 10+ per quarter to 1, on average.
- Developed and instructed technical training courses for Novell customers
- Coding in C, C#, .Net, C++, and Java on the ZENworks (ZDM/ZCM) product
- Java, Hibernate, HSQL, SQL, J2EE programming

- Cross-platform (Linux, MAC, Windows) programming using Mono, C#, .Net languages
- SOA Web Services programming using SOAP and WSDL protocols
- Extensive work with Linux, Drivers, and Networking Protocols
- Agile programming experience, specifically using SCRUM model

July 2002- 2005 Novell, Inc

Support Engineer III

- Onsite experience for critical situations with Fortune 500 Companies
- You Make the Difference Award March 2005
- Customer Champion Award October 2003
- Third-tier Support ZENworks Suite of Products (13+ products)
- Extensive ZENworks knowledge about processes, logging, and code
- Implemented and managed ZENworks Deployment Project

May 2000- Aug. 2002 Novell, Inc.

ZENworks Test Engineer

- Logged and tracked bugs requiring proficient communication and time management skills to coordinate contact with developers, support, upper management and companies
- Extensive experience using ZEN Policies & Packages and MSI/NAL components
- Managed a test case set for validation and component level tests
- Validation and component testing on ZENworks for Desktops (ZfD) 3 And ZENworks for Desktop 3.2 using WinRunner Automation Toolkit
- Completed entire test case set on time according to project schedules for both ZfD 3 and ZfD 3.2

Education

2005-2007 University of Phoenix

Master of Business Administration (MBA)

1998-2002 Brigham Young University

Bachelor of Computer Science

Business Minor

Certifications

ZENworks Specialist Certification,

Certified Novell Engineer (CNE)

Certified Novell Administrator (CAN),

Certified Linux Engineer (CLE),

Linux Professional Institute- Level 1(LPI-L1), LPI- Intermediate

References

Available upon request